Register of the Russia. Posol'stvo (U.S.) Records, 1897-1947.
Hoover Institution Archives
- Russian Supply Committee Office File, 1915-1918.
  - Military Technical Department (Box 373)
    - Invoices (Box 374)
      - 1915 (Folder 1)
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 2)
    - Printed matter (Folder 3-5)
      Available on microfilm reels 438 and 439
    - Reports
      - Air Force Administration, Petrograd (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 439
      - Main Military Technical Administration
        - Electrical Technical Department (Folder 7)
        - Fortification Department, 1917 (Box 375)
          - October (Folder 1)
          - November (Folder 2)
            Available on microfilm reel 440
        - Technical Department, 1917
          - October (Folder 3)
          - November (Folder 4)
          - December (Folder 5)
  - Mission of Ways of Communication (Box 376)
    - Correspondence
      - 1917 (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 441
      - 1918 (Folder 2)
    - Ledgers (Folder 3-4)
  - Mission of Ways of Communication
    - Orders, Administrative (Folder 5)
  - Naval Department (Box 377)
    - General (Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 442
    - Strunnikov, Vasilii
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Blueprints (Folder 3-6)
      - Blueprints (Box 378, Folder 1-6)
      - Blueprints (Box 379, Folder 1-2)
      - Correspondence (Folder 3)
      - Printed matter (Folder 4)
      - Reports (Folder 5)
      - Specifications (Folder 6-8)
  - Report and Statistics Department (Box 380)
    - Commission for Supervision of Fulfillment of Orders (Folder 1)
    - Machinery Department (Folder 2)
    - Military Technical Department (Folder 3)
    - Naval Department
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 4)
      - 1917-1918 (Folder 5)
  - Transportation Commission. (see also Transportation Department)
    - Minutes of board sessions
      - 1915-1916 (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 443
      - 1916 (Folder 7)
    - Reports (Folder 8-9)
  - Transportation Department (Box 381)
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - Russian General Staff, Petrograd
          - 1915 (Folder 1)
          - 1916
            - January-April (Folder 2)
            - April-May (Folder 3)
            - June-July (Folder 4)
            - July-August (Folder 5)
        - Russian Government Committee, London (Folder 6)
      - Reports (Folder 7-10)
        Available on microfilm reel 444
      - Time book (Box 382, Folder 1)
    - Commercial Agent
      - Charter parties (Folder 2)
        Available on microfilm reel 445
      - Report
        - "Otchet Agenta Ministerstva Torgovli i Promyshlennosti v Vashingtone za 1916." Mimeographed copy (Folder 3)
        - "Prilozhenie No. 6a." Mimeographed copy (Folder 4)
    - Piers' Security Subdivision (Folder 5)
    - Russo-Baltic Car Works (Folder 6)
- Card File, 1906-1920.
  Available on microfilm reels 445-446
  Personnel records, purchase orders, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Division of Supplies (Box 382)
    - Employees (Box 383)
    - Mission of Ways of Communication (Box 384)
      - Employees
      - Office supply (Box 385)
        Available on microfilm reel 446
  - Russian Supply Committee
    - Artillery Commission -- employees (Box 386-387.)
    - Mission of Ways of Communication -- employees--see Card File/Division of Supplies/Mission of Ways of Communication/Employees
    - Purchase orders (Box 388)
- Oversize File I, 1904-1928.
  Available on microfilm reels 446-481
  Blueprints, correspondence, diagrams, financial records, minutes, [and] Savings banks. (see also Subagencies/Financial Agent/1919) General
  - General (Box 388)
    - Correspondence
      - 1918-1919 (Box 389)
        Available on microfilm reel 447
      - 1919 (Box 390)
        Available on microfilm reel 448
      - 1920-1922 (Box 391)
    - Financial records
    - Newspaper -- Vestnik Vremennogo Vserossiiskogo Pravitel'stva, 1918-1919, Omsk (Box 392)
      Available on microfilm reel 449
  - Consulate General, Montreal -- savings bank (Box 393)
  - Division of Supplies
    - Financial Section
      - Commercial products
        - General (Box 394-403.)
          Available on microfilm reel 450-453
        - "Glavnyi Zhurnal Finansovaia chast: Otdel po snzbzheniiu pri Rossiiskom Posol'stve", 1920 (Box 398A.)
          Available on microfilm reel 452
        - Transportation of (Box 404)
          Available on microfilm reel 453
      - Employees (Box 405)
      - "Otchet Finansovoi Chasti Otdela po Snabsheniiu s l maia 1918 po 1 ianvaria 1919" (Box 406)
        Available on microfilm reel 454
    - General Chancery
      - Commercial products (Box 407-408.)
      - Warehouses
        - 1918 (Box 409)
          Available on microfilm reel 455
        - 1918-1919 (Box 410)
    - General Section--see General Chancery
    - Information and Report Section. Reports. (see also Special Commission for Evaluation of Division of Supplies' Property)
      - Division of Supplies -- "Otchet Otdela po Snabzheniiu pri Rossiiskom Poso'stve v Vashingtone na 1-e ianvaria 1919 goda." Mimeographed copy (Box 411)
      - Russian Supply Committee -- "Otchet Russkogo Zagotovitel'nogo Komiteta v Amerike"
        - Drafts (Box 412)
        - Part 3
          - Volume 1 (Box 413)
            Available on microfilm reel 456
          - Volume 2 (Box 414)
          - Volume 3 (Box 415)
    - Mission of Ways of Communication -- "Prilozhenie k otchetu o deiatel'nosti Missii Ministerstva Putei Soobshcheniia" (Box 416)
      Available on microfilm reel 457
      - 1918-1919
      - 1919-1920
    - Special Commission for Evaluation of Division of Supplies' Property (Box 417)
  - Financial Agent
    - Journals and ledgers
      - 1920-1921 (Box 418-419.)
        Available on microfilm reel 458
      - 1922 (Box 420)
        Available on microfilm reel 459
      - 1923 (Box 421)
    - Reports. Mimeographed copies
      - Division of Supplies
        - "Otchet o deiatel'nosti Otdela po Snabzheniiu pri Rossiiskom Posol'stve v Vashingtone"
          - 1918-1919 (Box 422)
            Available on microfilm reel 460
          - 1919-1920 (Box 423)
        - "Podrobnyi denezhno-imushshestvennyi otchet Otdela po Snabzheniiu pri Rossiiskom Posol'stve v Vashingtone"
          - 1918-1919 (Box 424)
            Available on microfilm reel 461
          - 1919-1920 (Box 425)
      - Financial Agent -- "Otchet Agenta Ministerstva Finansov pri Rossiiskom Posol'stve v Vashingtone"
        - Accounting report
          - 1920
            - January-April (Box 426)
              Available on microfilm reel 462
            - April-November (Box 427)
          - 1920-1921 (Box 428-429.)
            Available on microfilm reel 463
          - 1922-1923 (Box 430-431.)
            Available on microfilm reel 464
          - 1924-1925 (Box 432-433.)
            Available on microfilm reel 465
        - Cashier's report (Box 434)
        - Collection of appendices (Box 435)
          Available on microfilm reel 466
          - 1917-1920
          - 1920-1921 (Box 436)
        - Collection of control registers (Box 437)
        - Explanatory note
          - 1922-1923 (Box 438-439.)
            Available on microfilm reel 467
          - 1924-1925 (Box 440)
        - Explanatory note and accounting report
          - 1921-1922 (Box 441-442.)
            Available on microfilm reel 468
          - 1923-1924 (Box 443-444.)
            Available on microfilm reel 469
          - 1925-1926 (Box 445)
            Available on microfilm reel 470
          - 1927-1928 (Box 446-447.)
  - Military Agent
    - Mobile kitchen. Blueprints (Box 448)
    - Russian Revolution, 1917-1921 -- Civil War. Maps, 1920
    - Russian veterans in the United States, 1918
    - Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905
  - Russian State Control
    - General
      - Cash book
        - General (Box 449)
          Available on microfilm reels 471 and 471A
        - Petropavlovskii, Vitalii (Box 450)
          Available on microfilm reel 472
      - Registers of correspondence (Box 451)
        - 1917-1919
        - 1919-1920
    - Division of Supplies. Financial records
      - Journals (Box 452)
      - Ledgers (Box 453-454.)
        Available on microfilm reel 473
      - List of materials and supplies (Box 455)
  - Russian Supply Committee
    - Board sessions
      - 1915-1916 (Box 456)
        Available on microfilm reel 474
      - 1916
        - February-May
        - March-August (Box 457)
          Available on microfilm reel 475
        - August-December
      - 1916-1917 (Box 458)
        Available on microfilm reel 476
      - 1917 (Box 459)
        Available on microfilm reels 476 and 476A
      - 1917-1918 (Box 460)
        Available on microfilm reel 477
    - Commercial products (Box 461-462.)
      Available on microfilm reels 477 and 478
      - General
      - Agricultural Ministry (Box 463)
        Available on microfilm reel 478
      - All-Russian Cities Union
      - All-Russian Zemstvos Union
      - Artillery Commission
        - General
        - Technical Bureau
      - Central Military Industrial Committee (Box 464)
      - Commerce and Industry Ministry
      - Financial Department
      - Food Ministry (Box 465)
        Available on microfilm reel 479
      - Machinery Department
      - Metal Department
      - Military Technical Department
      - Mission of Ways of Communication
      - Naval Department (Box 466)
      - Petrograd Zemstvos and Cities Regional Committee
      - Technical Commission
    - Composition and structure (Box 467)
      Available on microfilm reel 480
    - Financial Department. Financial records
      - 1915-1917 (Box 468)
      - 1916-1917 (Box 469)
        Available on microfilm reel 481
      - 1917-1918 (Box 470)
    - Report and Statistics Division--see Commercial products
- Oversize File II, 1906-1918 (Box 471-473)
  - Blueprints (Box 471-472.)
  - Diagrams -- execution of contracts by American companies for the Russian Supply Committee and delivery of commercial products to Russia (Box 473)
- Memorabilia (Box 474)
  - Memorabilia (Box 474)
- Audio-Visual Materials
  153 prints and 9 postcards / 6 envelopes
  - 14 postcards of United States warships; 16 prints of stages in construction of submarines; 11 prints of a submarine Holland; and 12 prints of naval equipment of the "Long Arm" Company, Cleveland, Ohio, undated (Envelope A)
  - 7 prints and 14 postcards of stages in construction and launching of naval vessels; 7 prints of loading machines; and 8 prints of passenger ships, undated (Envelope B)
  - 1 print of outline map of the United States; 16 prints of United States airplanes; 6 prints depicting 12" shrapnel tests; 2 prints of Russian naval agents in the United States, undated (Envelope C)
  - 19 prints depicting maps, troops, and staff members of the III Russian Army, European War, 1914-1918; 39 prints of Russian refugees in Canada; 1 print of Captain Tsorn's grave, Washington D.C.?; 4 prints of Ataman Grigorii Semenov; and 1 postcard of a palace in Czernowitz, undated (Envelope D)
  - 27 prints of a Russian icebreaker Mikula Selianinovich, undated (Envelope mE)
  - 1 print of Russian naval agent in the United States; 3 prints depicting 12" shrapnel shells, Illarion Mishtoft, Russian Naval Agent in the United States, and representatives of Francis H. Clergue Company; 1 print of a machine gun; 1 print of British warship; two prints of engine room of a naval vessel; and 1 print of wheel house of a naval vessel, undated (Envelope mF)